<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>bgcicca</title><description>A minimal, small place where I post my articles.</description><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/</link><item><title>Electron Apps: Balancing Modern UI and Performance</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/electron-performance/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/electron-performance/</guid><description>Electron has revolutionized desktop app development, but its reliance on browser-like technology has sparked debates. Can it deliver performance on par with native apps, or are we sacrificing too much for a slick UI?</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Everything You Need to Know About Types in TypeScript</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/types-in-typescript/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/types-in-typescript/</guid><description>TypeScript introduces static typing to JavaScript, making code safer and more predictable. Learn how types work, why they matter, and how to use them effectively.</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Could DeepSeek Be the Democratization of AI?</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/deepseek-ai-democratization/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/deepseek-ai-democratization/</guid><description>The emergence of DeepSeek challenges OpenAI&apos;s dominance in the AI landscape by offering an equally powerful, open-source alternative. Explore how this shift could democratize access to advanced AI technology and foster a more inclusive and innovative ecosystem.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Accessible Applications for the Visually Impaired</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/building-accessible-applications-for-the-visually-impaired/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/building-accessible-applications-for-the-visually-impaired/</guid><description>Creating accessible applications is more than just a technical challenge; it&apos;s a step toward inclusivity. Learn practical strategies to make your digital products accessible to visually impaired users, including best practices for screen readers, image alt text, and beyond.</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Python, JavaScript, and C++ Rule the Programming World</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/python-js-perl-c-cpp/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/python-js-perl-c-cpp/</guid><description>In the &apos;90s, Perl dominated the scripting world with regex prowess, but Python arrived at just the right moment to shift the game. Meanwhile, JavaScript rose to fame as the backbone of front-end development. Dive into how CPython and Node.js shape these languages and why it&apos;s dangerous to idolize programming languages.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 16:50:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>PowerShell Zero to Hero for DevOps (the definitive guide)</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/posh-zero-to-hero/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/posh-zero-to-hero/</guid><description>PowerShell isn’t just another command-line tool; it’s a powerhouse for DevOps automation. Let’s talk scripts, workflows, and why PowerShell should be your new best friend.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bash, Fish, and Zsh: Choosing Your Shell</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/choosing-your-shell/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/choosing-your-shell/</guid><description>When it comes to choosing a shell, Bash, Fish, and Zsh are the heavy hitters. They all have their fanbases, quirks, and strengths, but which one is right for you? Let’s break it down—no fluff, just real talk about their pros and cons.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 06:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Let’s Talk About JavaScript Error Handling?</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/js-error-handling/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/js-error-handling/</guid><description>JavaScript has always had a bit of a rough relationship with error handling. Try-catch blocks? They’re like duct tape for your code—they get the job done, but not without adding bulk and sometimes making things messier. But now, there’s a potential game-changer on the horizon: the Safe Assignment Operator (`??=`).</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Haskell Is Less Scary Than It Looks</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/why-haskell/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/why-haskell/</guid><description>Haskell often gets a bad rap for being overly mathematical or cryptic, but it’s not as hard as it seems. With features like type inference, pure functions, and extreme abstraction, you might even find yourself writing a browser in just 600 lines of code. Let’s dive into why Haskell deserves a second look.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>From Astro.js Rookie to a Successful GitHub Pages Build</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/from-astro-js-rookie-to-a-successful-github-pages-build/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/from-astro-js-rookie-to-a-successful-github-pages-build/</guid><description>A detailed guide on my journey to building and deploying a website with Astro.js and GitHub Pages.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 06:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Modern Vim on Windows Setup</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/modern-vim-on-windows-setup/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/modern-vim-on-windows-setup/</guid><description>A comprehensive guide to setting up Vim on Windows for modern web development workflows.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>When Was the Last Time You Programmed Just for Fun?</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/when-was-the-last-time-you-programmed-just-for-fun/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/when-was-the-last-time-you-programmed-just-for-fun/</guid><description>In today&apos;s fast-paced tech world, it seems like every line of code has to have a purpose. Developers are often caught up in building the next big thing, creating apps to boost their portfolios or even solving complex business problems. But when was the last time you just sat down to code for the sheer joy of it? To build something without a deadline, without a client, and without any expectations? If you can&apos;t remember, you might be missing out on one of the most valuable aspects of being a developer: recreational programming.</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shallow Knowledge vs. Deep Knowledge: The Key to Standing Out in Today’s Tough Job Market</title><link>https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/shallow-knowledge-vs-deep-knowledge/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgcicca.github.io/posts/shallow-knowledge-vs-deep-knowledge/</guid><description>Alright, let’s get real about something many of us have been thinking lately: knowledge isn’t just one thing, right? In tech (or any field, really), there’s a big difference between shallow knowledge and deep knowledge. One is quick and flashy but often short-lived, while the other is rooted, unshakeable, and usually way more valuable in the long run. And with how rough the job market’s been this year, understanding this difference could mean everything for your career.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:15:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>